Cookbook for Benchmarking Products and Services
Welcome back to this session on benchmarking.
What we’re going to look at, is how we do a benchmarking study.
It’s really pretty fundamentally simple on how we do quantitative benchmarking,
or Sigma benchmarking, quality benchmarking. Step number one is we go out and we define
the processes that we want to benchmark.
Step two, for each process we define what is critical.
What things must go right. And for each one of those critical elements,
we count the number of defects.
And get the total number of units, establish our defect rate,
and then convert that information to the Sigma scale
of measure. And finally, step five is we plot Sigma's.
Now, that's really pretty simple. What I wind up with is a simple graph
of DPMO,
defects per million opportunities. By Sigma.
For example, One Sigma, Two, Three, Four, Five, Six.
And the line that converts our DPMO into Sigma.
Then for all of those defined processes
and critical to quality characteristics. I plot them.
On my chart.
And, I look at where the centroid of that tends to be.
In this case, right about in here.
And that tells me overall what my Sigma capability is. Now, here's what's interesting.
Suppose, I go out and I do that in my processes, and I find a little group over here.
That's a pretty big difference
in defects per million opportunities between these two.
Well, what I’d do is go over here and seek those few out. And ask myself the question,
what are they doing fundamentally different in identifying
their critical X’s and controlling those critical X’s,
in order to make their quality so much better?
Then what I would do is transfer that understanding back into this group.
Through teaching, etc.
That's how we go about using benchmarking to create improvements.
Understand where we're at and where we need to go.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.